http://www.michaelnobbs.com/privacy-policy

Contact
Privacy Policy 21st May 2018Who I amHello, I'm Michael (Nobbs). Go Gently is my website and this is my privacy policy.I hope that is policy is clear and easy to understand and will help you see that I take your privacy and the care of any information that you trust me with very seriously.My aim is to only ask for and make use of information that is essential for the running of my business. I never sell, rent or trade your information with others for marketing purposes.This Privacy Policy details when and why I collect your personal information, how I use it, the limited conditions under which I may disclose it to others and how I keep it secure.Mailing ListsThe main use that I make use of your personal information is if you sign up for one or more of my mailing lists.I currently have three permanent mailing lists all delivered by a third party provider, MailChimp.THESE LISTS ARE:The Go Gently Letter list.The One Thing Today podcast list.Creative Circle members' list.From time to time I may also create other temporary email lists that you may join if you take one of my courses. These lists will only be used to deliver course information and will be deleted once the course is finished.I gather statistics around email opening and clicks using industry standard technologies to help me monitor and improve my offerings. For more information, please see MailChimp’s privacy notice.You can unsubscribe from my mailing lists at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any of my emails or by contacting me at michael@michaelnobbs.com.OTHER POTENTIAL USES OF YOUR EMAIL ADDRESS.I will store and make use of your name and email address if you are one of my mentoring clients. I use Google G Suite to handle my work emails and address book (G Suite & Google Cloud Platform Commitments to the GDPR).I am currently deciding how long it is useful and necessary to keep emails from clients. Once I reached a decision I will post that here, but in the meantime, you are of course welcome to contact me to ask what emails I have from you (and ask me to delete them if you would like me to) by contacting me at michael@michaelnobbs.com.ONLINE APPOINTMENT BOOKING SYSTEMIf you book appointments with me via my Calendly account then they will also hold a copy of the information you supply (Calendly's privacy policy). Your appointment will be stored on my Google calendar.Sales initiated on my websiteMost sales of my offerings or books initiated on this site are handled by either Amazon(books) or Teachable (courses) and I don't hold any data relating to the sales.In the case of courses booked via Teachable, your details will be added, with your permission, to the relevant course email list for the duration of the course.ONE-TO-ONE SESSION SALESThe one exception to the holding of personal data related to sales is if you book one-to-one mentoring sessions with me. In this case. I will store your details both on my work email account and within my accounting software, Freeagent. I will need to keep a record of your purchase for as long as is legally required by HMRC in the UK for the purposes of my tax returns.If you book a block of mentoring sessions with me you are able to pay via bank transfer or by credit/debit card via a payment processor. I offer use of Stripe and PayPal for the processing of payments and if you use one of those methods I will receive limited information about your purchase from them. Your payment details are stored on their systems.Stripe terms and conditionsPayPal terms and conditionsWebsite cookiesThis site is currently hosted by Squarespace. I have turned off their analytics cookies and activity log and to the best of my knowledge believe that this site now gathers no information about your visits.Squarespace does require the use of certain cookies to allow for the smooth functioning of this website. You can read more about these "functional and required" cookies over on Squarespace.Embedded content from other websitesArticles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracking your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.Access to your personal informationYou are entitled to view, amend, or delete the personal information that I hold. Contact me at michael@michaelnobbs.com.Changes to this Privacy NoticeThis Privacy Policy is shiny and new and I suspect will be tweaked over the coming weeks and months until it is fine-tuned. After that, I will aim to review and update it at least once a year and will provide details here whenever I do that.If you have any thoughts or suggestions for how this notice (or my handling of your information) can be improved or if you believe there is anything missing please let me know at michael@michaelnbbs.com.
The Go Gently LetterMost months Occasionally, I send out a short email newsletter called the Go Gently Letter.In the letter  I share a little about my ongoing journey to live gently and create gently and in doing so I hope to inspire you to take small steps to do the same.
Subscribe
Instagram: Learning to live gently
